{"test_questions": [[{"question": "The conformational changes from the T to the R state is initiated by", "opta": "binding of oxygen to the heme", "optb": "movement of the proximal histidine towards the heme", "optc": "movement of the F-helix, which contains the proximal His", "optd": "reorganization of protein-protein contacts between the individual subunits", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An allosteric activator", "opta": "increases the binding affinity", "optb": "decreases the binding affinity", "optc": "stabilizes the R state of the protein", "optd": "both (a) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Bisphosphoglycerate (BPG) cannot bind to the oxygenated R state of hemoglobin because", "opta": "it is displaced from the heme by oxygen", "optb": "it is displaced from the heme by movement of the proximal histidine", "optc": "its binding pocket becomes too small to accommodate BPG", "optd": "BPG binds to the R state with the same affinity as the T state", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The Hill coefficient (nH) for myoglobin and hemoglobin are respectively", "opta": "2.8 and 1.0", "optb": "1.0 and 2.8", "optc": "1.2 and 4.5", "optd": "4.5 and 1.2", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When protein binds two ligands in a non-cooperative manner, then the x-intercept of the Scatchard Plot is", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "not defined", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "O2 binding to hemoglobin results in", "opta": "100-fold higher affinity for the last O2 bound than for the first", "optb": "extensive protein conformational change", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "100-fold lower affinity for the last O2 bound than for the first", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In hemoglobin, allosteric effects occur", "opta": "only in humans", "optb": "for maintaining Fe in the Fe2+ state", "optc": "to minimize oxygen delivery to the tissues", "optd": "to maximize oxygen delivery to the tissues", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A protein that binds two ligands in a non-cooperative manner will show", "opta": "a sigmodial binding curve", "optb": "a hyperbolic binding curve", "optc": "a linear Scatchard Plot", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Small molecules affect hemoglobin (Hb) by", "opta": "decreasing Hb affinity for O2", "optb": "increasing [H+]", "optc": "increasing Hb affinity for O2", "optd": "increasing [H+] and decreasing Hb affinity for O2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A protein that shows infinite cooperative for binding of n ligands will", "opta": "show a Hill coefficient (nH) of 0.0", "optb": "only be found in either the unliganded form or the fully liganded form", "optc": "show a Hill coefficient (nH) of n", "optd": "both (b) and (c)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The specificity of a ligand binding site on a protein is based on", "opta": "the absence of competing ligands", "optb": "the amino acid residues lining the binding site", "optc": "the presence of hydrating water molecules", "optd": "the opposite chirality of the binding ligand", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}